Let's discuss more about the OSM model.
So if you see in this diagram, there is an application layer, in the application layer
we will represent our requester data, so whatever you are sending, like a high message
or sending username and password, so that will be the data.
So, in the fourth layer of the OSM model, so we will call our data, whatever the high
or any username and password as a segment, so why we are calling as a segment, because
data will be splitred into multiple parts, okay.
So let's see an example, so if there is a 30 MB of data, so it will be splitred into multiple
chunks, okay, so 5 MB, 5 MB, 5, 5, 5, 5, whatever, okay.
So the data will be probably splitred into multiple segments, okay, so that's why we are
calling our data as a segment, okay, in the transport layer, so we already discussed
there is two protocols, only TCP and another one is UDP, so this will be either TCP will
be added or UDP will be added, okay.
So after that, we have a network layer, in the network layer, we already know, so sorry
for that, in the transport layer, one more thing will be added, that was a port number
of the protocol, if it's a HTTP, then the port number will be 80, if it's a HTTP, yes, then
the port number will be 443, if it's FTP, then the port number will be 21, we will discuss
the protocols and port number briefly in upcoming videos later on, so in the network layer,
we will call our the segments as a packet, okay, so that was our data packet, so we already
know in the network layer, the source IP address and the destination IP address will be
added, if the data will be like this, okay, transport header like TCP and the source IP
destination IP and the data, we will call this entire thing as a packet, okay, so let's
take a look here, in the network layer, the source IP destination IP, this will be added
in each of the segments, okay, each of the segments, the source IP and destination IP
will be added, the data needs to be splitter, why we need to split the data, because
as per the internet sphere, if the internet has paid us 5 MVP as per second, we need
to segment this data into chunks, right, into divide this data into multiple chunks, right,
multiple segments, so we are segmenting the data and we are adding source IP and the destination
IP in each of the segments, okay, each of the segment that we segmented by the transport
layer, okay, source and destination IP will be added, right, so once we add the IP address
in the network layer, then our packets will be come up to the data link layer, in the
data link layer, we know the frame, okay, sorry, we know the MAC address will be added,
the source MAC and the destination MAC, right, so here, now we have a one more thing and the
source MAC and the destination MAC address will be added in each of the segments, like
before, okay, so finally, our data will be reaching to the physical layer and our data
will be converted to zero sand ones, right, because our data need to communicate through
the cable, it's array 45 or any fiber optic cable, it's new, it's need to be transferred
to the cable, so we are transforming our data into the bits, okay, so we will call it
us frames, so once you add the MAC address, our data packets will be called as a frames
and once it reaches to the physical layer, this will be called us, called us bits, okay,
so this will be in the protocol data units, okay, PDUs, we will say it as a PDU, okay,
data segments back at frames and bits, okay, so I'll discuss one more time, whenever
the data will be reached to the transport layer, we will call our data as a segments,
yes, it will be segmented into multiple chunks, multiple segments, so once the data reaches
to the network layer, we will be call our data as packets, one packet, packet to packet
tree and once the data reaches to the data link layer, it will call our packets, it's
a frames, right, so once it reaches to the physical layer, so this data needs to be transferred
to zero sand ones, we already discuss, it's need to be transferred to the cable, right,
on place to one source to, on destination, so we are transforming our data to bits, okay,
this is the entire process of protocol data units, okay, so let's hope of this video,
and we will discuss the TCP and UDP, the free in the next video, thank you for watching.